htmlbasictutor.ca 2006-09-26

# HTML Basic Tutor - Privacy Policy

## Type of Information Gathered

### Web Server Information

My web server provides me with the following reports:

**General Summary** \- Displays the most important overall statistics.

**Request Reports** \- Number of page requests by month, day and hour.

**Domain Report** \- Countries that requests have come from. 

**Organization Report** \- Organizations that requests have come from. 

**Refer Reports** \- Referrerals that had to be redirected, failed referrerals that had to be redirected, broken links and list of servers that referred people to my site (how people are finding my site). The referals are recorded as requests from servers, not individual visitors.

**Search Word Report** \- The words people typed into the search engine to find my site.

**Browsers** \- Details of the version and type of browsers used to view my site.

**Operating System Report** \- What operating systems were used by the visitors to my site. 

**Status Code Report** \- Lists each HTTP status code that you received. 

**Files and Directories** \- The files requested to be viewed, the type of files requested and which directory they are in. Also, which files were downloaded. 

None of the reports above can identify you personally. These statistics are used by me to improve my marketing plan and make improvements to my site. 

### Information You Provide

Information you provide to me is kept in the strictest of confidence. It will not be released to anyone unless I am served with a court order to release this information.

### Spam

I have a zero tolerance policy regarding spam. If you provide me with your email address you have to request that I contact you. If you are interested in joining my mailing list you have to request this and I will reply asking for confirmation.

### Electronic Payments

PayPal is used for payments. View PayPal's [Privacy](http://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=p/gen/ua/policy_privacy-outside "PayPal - User Agreement - Privacy Policy") statement.

### Database

If you wish to determine is you are in our database please Contact Us with Database at HTML Basic Tutor in the subject.

To check what information we have in our database on you please Contact Us with Check Database at HTML Basic Tutor in the subject.

To remove yourself from our database please send us an email with the subject "REMOVE". You will receive one final email from me confirming that all information about you has been removed and after that, you will be permanently removed from our records. 

## Cookies

Cookies are used with this site. The cookie remembers which of the menu items you had open when you return to a page. That's it. No personal information is collected.

If you wish to purchase this book, PayPal uses cookies. See [PayPal's Privacy Statement](http://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=p/gen/ua/policy_privacy-outside#information) on how they are used.

## Scripts

Javascript is used to show and hide menu items. It is also used to insert the date and page location of each page. No person information is collected and no harm is done to your computer.

## Security Systems

All electronic payments are processed through PayPal. Please view PayPal's [security](http://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_security-center-outside) features.

## Forums and Message Boards

There is a message group set up for the purchasers of the book at [Yahoo](http://groups.yahoo.com/group/htmlbasicstutor/). [Yahoo's privacy policy](http://privacy.yahoo.com/privacy/us/).

## Linked Sites

Links within the HTML 4.01 Basics Simplified ebook and on the accompanying website are provided for your convenience. I have no control over what information is collected or how it is used therefore by clicking the links provided you accept the responsibility to verify how the site collects and uses information.

## Unsubscribe from Our Mailing List

If at anytime you wish to be removed from my records send me an email with the subject REMOVE. You will receive one final email from me confirming that you have been removed from all records.

## Contact Us

HTML Basic Tutor  
Owned and Operated by SRT Services   
# 108 10698 151 A Street, Surrey, British Columbia, Canada V3R 8T6 

Phone: 604 619 4945 Fax: 604 588 9937 (please call before faxing)

Email: HTML Basic Tutor

HTML 4.01 Basics Simplified ebook

Basic HTML Code  
Articles

Basic HTML Code  
Tips 

Web Design  
Tutorials 

Web Design  
Tutorial Videos

Web Design  
Resources

Website  
Building Tools

SEO - Search Engine Optimization

HTML Basic Tutor  
Information

If you need information on creating your own privacy policy:  
Visit James S. Huggins' Refrigerator Door [Privacy in the Internet Age](http://www.jamesshuggins.com/h/pri1/privacy.htm ">Privacy in the Internet")
